Application

Harry Vermeulen Weezenhof 2523 6536JH Nijmegen h.p.j.vermeulen@gmail.com +31 (0) 24 3440493

I am writing to you in regard to the position of Graphic/Digital designer - 24h/week, remote (6+ month contract)

After graduating from Design Interactions at the Royal College of Art in London, I have spent the last 15 years in Japan, designing and implementing Canon's camera user interfaces, Canon's office printer user interfaces, mobile applications and interactive installations for museums. My work has been well received, and in 2024, 2021 and 2012 we have won the esteemed design awards with the 'Powershot V10' camera, the 'Powershot PICK' camera and the 'Image Finder' museum installation.

As much as I loved my colleagues in Japan and enjoyed working there, I am now looking for a new challenge where I can continue to grow as designer and tap into my passion to design for our future, using contemporary technology and interaction design to realize the hopes and dreams of people.

Attached to this cover letter you will find my resumé and portfolio. An interactive portfolio is available on my website at http://www.harryvermeulen.com

I really look forward to discussing my experience and qualifications with you in more detail.

Thank you so much for your time.

Best regards, Harry Vermeulen

Resumé

Personal information

Name: Harry Vermeulen

Born: Nijmegen, the Netherlands (17th of April 1984)

Gender: Male Nationality: Dutch

Address: Weezenhof 2523, 6536JH Nijmegen, the Netherlands

Phone: +31 (0) 24 3440493 E-mail: h.p.j.vermeulen@gmail.com Website: http://www.harryvermeulen.com

Characteristics

I am a full stack designer who is passionate about technology and people, and how design can bring the two together through beautiful and intuitive interaction. I have a special love for the synergy of analog and digital interaction and the value of joy in the products we use in our daily lives. I thrive while working with other people and have a positive and motivating influence on my team. I'm the most happy designing innovative solutions for complex problems, creating interactive prototypes, working together with other dicsiplines to create products that enrich our lives.

Skills

User Experience Design, Interaction Design, Concept Development, Creative brainstorming, Prototyping, Programming, Graphic design, Typography, Multi-touch interaction, Future narrative design, Light interaction design, Sound design, Videography, Photography, C++, Objective-C, openFrameworks, OpenGL/GLSL Shaders, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Premiere Pro, InDesign, Audition, Final Cut Pro, 3D Studio MAX (Modeling/Texturing/Animation), HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, SQL, Processing, Arduino, Electronics (sensors, actuators, transistors, relays, etc.)

Education

MA Design Interactions

Royal College of Art in London, United Kingdom https://www.rca.ac.uk/study/schools/school-design/

BSc Industrial Design

University of Technology in Eindhoven, the Netherlands https://www.tue.nl/en/education/bachelor-college/bachelor-industrial-design

Work experience

User Experience Designer 2015-2024 Canon Design Center, Tokyo, Canon Headquarters https://global.canon/en/design/

Responsabilities

Design and development of Canon's camera and mobile application user interfaces (7 years). Design and development of Canon's office printer user interfaces (3 years). Facilitation of close collaboration with international group companies like Océ, NTWare, Canon USA and Canon Hong Kong. Project leader for several future concept development projects. Project leader for user centered camera design projects. Mobile application design and character animation design for the Powershot PICK camera. Lead light and sound interaction designer for several of Canon's concepts and products.

Achievements

Won the 2024 IF Design Award with the 'Powershot V10' camera https://ifdesign.com/en/winner-ranking/project/powershot-v10/611108

Won the 2021 Good Design Award with the 'Powershot PICK' camera https://www.g-mark.org/en/gallery/winners/9e4db1e6-803d-11ed-af7e-0242ac130002

Won several patents related to innovative camera design and camera operability https://patents.google.com/?inventor="harry vermeulen"

Work experience

Interaction Designer/Programmer 2010-2014 ATR Creative, Kyoto http://www.atr-c.jp

Responsabilities

Design and development of interactive installations for museums, mobile applications related to museums and illustrated maps, web development, videography, creative brainstorm sessions, multitouch interaction design, graphic design, business model development

Achievements

Won the 2012 Good Design Award with 'Image Finder' http://www.g-mark.org/award/describe/39258

Designed and developed interactive installations installed in Japanese national museums http://vimeo.com/51121178 http://vimeo.com/20867960 http://vimeo.com/92710931

Designed and developed 10+ mobile applications http://vimeo.com/104217717 http://vimeo.com/38207556

Designer / Owner 2011-2013 HV design, Kyoto http://www.harryvermeulen.com

Achievements

Designed and developed a 3D bird watching game for a 200 inch, 201 viewing angles 3D display developed by NICT. The game is on public display at the northern tower of Grand Front Osaka. http://vimeo.com/68699705 http://www.nict.go.jp/publication/NICT-News/1311/03.html

Designed and developed the 'Smell Player' software for the venture company 'Aroma Join'. http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pq_RMm6HNgw

Awards

Won the 2024 iF Design Award with the 'Powershot V10' camera https://ifdesign.com/en/winner-ranking/project/powershot-v10/611108

Won the 2022 iF Design Award with the 'Powershot PICK' camera https://ifdesign.com/en/winner-ranking/project/powershot-px/330081

Won the 2021 Good Design Award with the 'Powershot PICK' camera https://www.g-mark.org/en/gallery/winners/9e4db1e6-803d-11ed-af7e-0242ac130002

Won several patents related to innovative camera design and camera operability https://patents.google.com/?inventor="harry vermeulen"

Work published in 'See Yourself Sensing: Redefining Human Perception' (Madeline Schwartzman) http://www.amazon.com/See-Yourself-Sensing-Redefining-Perception/dp/1907317295/

Won the 2012 Good Design Award with 'Image Finder' http://www.g-mark.org/award/describe/39258

Excellence in Research Award 2012 http://www.atr.co.jp/prize/prize2012_j.html

Work published in 'ROBOT: Artificial Intelligence, Cybernetics and The Machine' (Duncan McCorquodale) http://www.amazon.com/ROBOT-Artificial-Intelligence-Cybernetics-Machine/dp/1908966866

Languages

Dutch, English, Japanese